Guide to the Olive Tjaden papers, 1919-1980
Tjaden, Olive papers, 1919-1980
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Olive Tjaden papers, 1919-1980
15-6-2919
Olive Tjaden.
6.2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, scrapbooks, diaries, photographs, business and financial records, lists, clippings, broadsides, diplomas, certificates, licenses, framed images, drawings, watercolors, books, leaded glass items, and architectural instruments.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, scrapbooks, diaries, photographs, business and financial records, lists and other records pertaining to the practice of architecture and the renovation of Tjaden Hall on the Cornell campus, clippings, broadsides, diplomas, certificates, licenses, and other papers. Collection includes framed images, drawings, watercolors, and other visual images deriving from Tjaden's professional career, with numerous references to individual clients and patrons. Also includes books, leaded glass items, and architectural instruments.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Olive Tjaden VanSickle, distinguished alumna of the College of Architecture, Art and Planning at Cornell, began her career with a Long Island architect and later opened her own firm. She designed more than 2,000 buildings during 20 years of practice in New York, including her own home in Garden City, Long Island. In 1945 she moved to Florida and participated in the extensive development there. Now retired, she lives in Fort Lauderdale, Florida.
Tjaden's work includes a number of large estates on Long Island and in upstate New York, churches, and commercial buildings. In Florida, she continued her work as an architect of residential garden apartments.
At one time in her career, Tjaden was the only woman member of the American Institute of Architects. Among her other professional activities, she was an inspector for the Federal Housing Administration and program director for the Museum of Fine Arts in Fort Lauderdale.
Tjaden Hall (formerly Franklin Hall), on the Cornell University campus, was renamed in her honor in 1980.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, scrapbooks, diaries, photographs, business and financial records, lists and other records pertaining to the practice of architecture and the renovation of Tjaden Hall on the Cornell campus, clippings, broadsides, diplomas, certificates, licenses, and other papers. Collection includes framed images, drawings, watercolors, and other visual images deriving from Tjaden's professional career, with numerous references to individual clients and patrons. Also includes books, leaded glass items, and architectural instruments.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Tjaden, Olive.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University--Buildings.
Subjects:
Architecture--Aesthetics.; Architecture--Conservation and restoration.; Architecture--Designs and plans.; Architecture--Working drawings.; Women architects.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
Occupations:
Architects.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Personal And Family Records
Correspondence
Photographs
Travel
Miscellaneous
Series II. Professional Records and Materials
Diplomas, Certificates, Licenses, etc.
Projects
Photographs of Professional Work
Publications and Presentations
Financial and Legal Records
Miscellaneous Professional Papers
Honoraria, Awards, etc.
Dedication of Olive Tjaden Hall, Cornell University, June 12 1981
Series III. Artworks
Series IV. Architectural Plans and Drawings
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Personal And Family Records
  - Correspondence
    - "Letters of long ago" (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Hilda Tjaden correspondence and miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "Personal stuff" (includes correspondence, postcards) (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Carl Johnson letters, etc. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Personal correspondence (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Photographs
    - Color slide (Box 1)
    - Tjaden and family, friends (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Family and friends (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Olive, Hilda (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Olive, childhood (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "Mom and Pop" (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Hilda's pictures of Papa and two sisters; sister along; Moer and Fahr's wedding anniversary; antique cards (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Olive and friends (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Olive (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Family photos (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Unidentified photos (many of Tjaden) (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
    - Slides and slide viewer (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Hilda Francke Tjaden (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Unidentified family and friends (at least one of Hilda Tjaden) (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Unidentified family and friends (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Parents' house (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Cornell University (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Tjaden in kimono (Box 19)
    - Portrait of Olive and Mother (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Portrait of Olive Tjaden (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Slides (Box 14)
  - Travel
    - 3 travel scrapbooks (Box 1)
    - Travel scrapbook: "Gala Springtime Cruise, S.S. Independence, Feb. 28 - May 4, 1967", 1967 (Box 2)
    - Orient, Europe (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Cornell University Pooled Life Income Fund (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Pistol target shooting (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Materials relating to separation from Carl Johnson (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Diaries (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Bound volumes: The Hymnal, The Christian's Companion, "Roster of Women/Florida" (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Grospapa's painting (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Painting palette, MU-2510 (Box 5)
    - Triangle, MU-2511 (Box 5)
    - Box of drafting tools, MU-2512 (Box 5)
    - Box of drafting tools, MU-2513 (a-m) (Box 5)
      Includes ink well, 2 water beakers, drafting tools (several sets), 2 triangle rulers, 2 compasses, painting palette, and pencil leads.
    - Materials relating to separation from Carl Johnson (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Cornell images, postcards, and poster, 1921-1924 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Personal documents, 1911-1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Miscellany, personal, Undated (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
    - Legal documents, 1977-1996 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
    - Rosewell Van Sickle, Undated (Box 19, Folder 19)
      Germany and England's Sea Fleets
    - Sea flag, Undated; MU-2015 (Box 19)
      Brown and blue
    - Certificates, 1884-1947 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Diplomas received by Roswell Charles Van Sickle; public school and church certificates received by Hilda Francke; church certificate received by Traugott Francke
    - John G. Tjaden National Bible Institute certificate (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - John G. Tjaden Engineering License (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Francke coat of arms (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Series II. Professional Records And Materials
  - Diplomas, Certificates, Licenses, etc.
    - Architect's Certificate of Registration, State of New York (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - State of Florida architect's certificate, January 11, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - B.A. diploma (dates crossed out) (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - New York State diploma in architecture (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - State of New Jersey architecture license (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Dale Carnegie course certificate (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - State of New York architecture license (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Projects
    - Savage Farm Project (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Project proposal and specifications, Proposal for renovations to Parish House for St. James Church, Elmhurst, Queens; specifications of the labor and materials required in the erection and completion of Bellerose Baptist Church; specifications of the labor and materials required in the erection and completion of Inwood Beach Club, Atlantic Beach, N.Y.; specifications for residence and attached garage for Mr. and Mrs. Harold Jacobi, Woodmere, Long Island (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Builders' information: Comparative Architectural Details; Lead Industries Association publications; decor molding business card; Hamlin colored texturing plaster leaflet; assorted clippings (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Brochure for "Waterfront Estate on Royal Palm Plaza" (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Specifications and contact for 9 unit apartment on Hendricks Island, Ft. Lauderdale, Florida (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Professional Work
    - Scrapbook of professional work (Box 1)
    - Tjaden's residence, Olive and workmen on job (3); exterior (4); main entrance door detail and bell; conservatory off living room, views of garden, cockatoo, main entrance tower with Tjaden silhouette on weather vane; 2 leaded glass windows; peacock leaded glass door from living room to terrace (2); Olive (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Tjaden's residence entrance (and Olive), living room and breakfast room (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Part of Senior Examination Exhibit of Olive F. Tjaden (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Harold Jacobi residence, Woodmere, Long Island, exterior; stairway; living room; dressing table; dining room - "I designed everything - not decorator" (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - V. Newman residence, Port Washington, Long Island (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Horace Hoffman house, Garden City, Long Island; Thomas Hewitt residence, Garden City, Long Island (3) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Arthur Marks residence, Woodmere, Long Island (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Oldsmobile dealership (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Oldsmobile dealership (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Residence for Vice President of L.I. Lighting Company, Bayshore, Long Island (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Mercury apartments, Fort Lauderdale, FL, residence of Dorothy Laman, unidentified residence, 208 Hendricks Isle, Fort Lauderdale, Fla. (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - C. Hammond Residence, Huntington, Long Island (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Sanford Jacobi residence, Woodmere, Long Island, exterior and interior views (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Inwood Beach Club (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified house interior and exterior (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Jacobi House, Woodmere, Long Island, reprint from House and Garden Magazine, "I designed all interiors, details, etc., not and 'outside' decorator." (Box 19)
    - Unidentified painting on interior wall (Box 9)
    - Printer's mock-up of advertisement for house designed by Tjaden (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous slides of Tjaden's work, including her apartment in 1977 (Box 13)
  - Publications and Presentations
    - Talk at Freedom's Foundation at Valley Forge (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Professional articles and reprints, Automotive Merchandising; Oldsmobile Dealer Round Table, v. 3, no. 2; Inwood Beach Club leaflet; Architectural Record, Aug. 1938; Architectural Record, "Building News" (Architectural Record reprint of Inwood Beach Club article); New York World's Fair 1939, "The Home Building Center," page featuring one of Tjaden's designs; booklet: "The Community Church of Garden City"; booklet: "For the Glory of God and the Youth of Whitestone," Grace Church, Whitestone, Long Island, N.Y.; Harper Method, Salon de Coiffure (leaflet); Mineola, Long Island, N.Y. (leaflet) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Articles and leaflets, House and Garden, May 1935 (Harold Jacobi home); The Suburban Homefinder, Spring 1937 (Thomas M. Hewett home); "Garden City Show Place" (Tjaden's home); Seawane Bungalows; residence of Mr. and Mrs. Donald S. Gibbs, Port Washington, Long Island, N.Y. (leaflet); residence of Mr. and Mrs. John D. Hensley, Port Washington, Long Island, N.Y. (leaflet); Mercury Apartments' Timber Ridge, Oyster Bay, Long Island, N.Y.; unidentified home (card) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - House & Garden, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - The Big Red Book, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Financial and Legal Records
    - 1950 Records; 1951-52, c. 1950-1952; Charlie's lot bought Oct. 20 1952 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 1952 Records; Wallace residence, #200 Hendricks Isle, Fort Lauderdale, Fla., 1952; Built in 1952, sold in 1953; north half of lot 8 bl. 4 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 1953 Records, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 1953 Income Tax; job #196 and job #28 records, 1953; Job #196 started 1952, sold 1953; job #28 started (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - 1954 Records, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - 1954 Income tax (joint); job #28 records, 1954; Lot 11, bl.4 (sold Jul. 1954) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Job #230 expenses (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - 1955 Income tax (joint); Job #30 records, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Job #30, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Photostats of Danaia Bank deposits, Job #230 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 1956 Records; 1956 Income tax; Job #30 records, 1957-60, 1956-1960 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence with Willis J. Zick, attorney, re: taxes; 810 expense checks; bond (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Jobs #200, 230, 300, 216, 20 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Mortgage deeds (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Professional Papers
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Clippings (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Miscellany, professional, 1942, Undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and articles, 1935-1995 (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
  - Honoraria, Awards, etc.
    - "Women of Achievement" volume (Box 2)
    - Honoraria, Notice of inclusion in 1968-69 edition of Personalities of the South; letter welcoming Tjaden as new Vice President of the Alumni Association of College of Architecture, Art and Planning, Cornell University, also 2 photographs of Tjaden at Cornell; press release re: Tjaden's address at New York Housing Show; World Center for Women's Archives certificate (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Publicity and honors (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Notices of inclusion in Who's Who in America and Who's Who in the South and Southwest (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Plaque acknowledging Olive Tjaden Van Sickle in "Who's Who and Why of Successful Florida Women, Premier Edition", MU-2014 (Box 19)
    - Front page of Brooklyn Daily Eagle, Saturday, Feb. 5, 1938 (year blackened out), with story about Tjaden "the first woman member of the Brooklyn chapter of the conservative American Institute of Architects", Mounted on cardstock (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Clipping: “Leading Ladies of U.S.” (Box 19)
  - Dedication of Olive Tjaden Hall, Cornell University, June 12 1981
    - Volume of photographs "presented to Olive Tjaden Van Sickle as a memento of the dedication of Olive Tjaden Hall, June 12, 1981, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York" (Box 1)
    - Volume of architectural drawings and photographs of Tjaden Hall (Box 2)
    - Cornell University Olive Tjaden Hall Renovation Schematic Design Submittal, Schwartz/Silver Architects, Inc., Aug. 18 1995 (Box 2)
    - Photographs: Tjaden Hall Dedication (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - K.C. Parsons Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - John Crowley Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Jason Seley Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Citation Renaming Franklin Hall Olive Tjaden Hall (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Information re: renovations (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Tjaden Hall dedication articles (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Tjaden Hall Dedication - correspondence (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Tjaden Hall Dedication - photographs (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Tjaden Hall Dedication - transcripts and tapes (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Cornell University Reunion Materials, 1981, 1983, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Photograph of Tjaden Hall (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Tjaden Hall dedication certificate (Box 4)
    - Photograph of Franklin Hall before rededication (Box 9)
    - Cornell correspondence re: Tjaden Hall and Van Sickle Art Gallery dedications, 1979-1997 (Box 11, Folder 7-14)
    - Cornell clippings, articles, miscellany re: Olive Tjaden and Tjaden Hall dedication, 1975-1995 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Tjaden Hall renovation project, correspondence, drawings, and photographs, 1966-1997 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Photographs: Tjaden Hall dedication plus one image of special exhibit case (Box 11, Folder 17-18)
    - Audiotapes (3) of Tjaden Hall dedication (Box 13)
    - Audiotape of Van Sickle Art Gallery dedication (Box 13)
- Series III. Artworks
  - Cut paper silhouettes of Olive Tjaden (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Original tracing - Tjaden weather vane, Garden City house (Mapcase-folder 39)
  - Designs for leaded glass windows in Tjaden's house, Garden City, Long Island (Box 6)
  - Pen and ink drawing of unidentified town scene (Box 9)
  - Charcoal drawing of unidentified castle[?] (Box 9)
  - Sketches of gate, open structure with weather vane (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Notes written on cardboard backings from two drawings/photos (Box 9)
  - Pen and ink drawings, Amiens, "A Baroque Doorway", English Renaissance, Spanish Renaissance, The Invalides, Saizhaus - German Renaissance, A Romanesque Detail, unidentified street scene, West Front of Branston, Lincolnshire, French Renaissance chair, window at San Lorenzo, Roman Corinthian order (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Pen and ink drawings (colored), Egyptian pattern detail, unidentified column capital, Greek decoration (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - 2 prints: N. Robert, N. Arras (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified pencil drawing of doorway and two children; painting of Venice scene; newspaper print of drawing of Yuletide cottage, designed by Tjaden; print of Venice scene (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Clipping from magazine of white bird with spread wings (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Still life painting by Tjaden (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Charcoal drawing of unidentified building exterior (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Pen and ink drawing of unidentified building exterior (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Reprints of artworks (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - 16" x 12" leaded glass panel depicting nobleman (Box 7)
  - 16" x 12" leaded glass panel depicting hunter (Box 8)
  - 16" x 12" leaded glass panel depicting hunter (Box 10)
  - 12" x 12" colored glass panel depicting owl (Box 15)
  - 15" x 19" leaded glass panel depicting a lady. (Box 18)
- Series IV. Architectural Plans and Drawings
  - Sketches for stained-glass windows (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Main Gate Entrance", Garden City, Long Island (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Sketches
  - Unidentified plot plan (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Catevenis residence, Ft. Lauderdale, Fla., Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Pencil drawings
  - Garvel residence (Job# 544), Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Blueprints
  - Christ residence (Job# 637), New Hyde Park, Long Island, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Hammond Residence (Job# 543), Huntington, Long Island, 1933-04 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    206 Kensington Road in Garden City, New York
  - Synagogue, Mineola, Long Island, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Pontiac dealership sketch; Socony Gas Station, Manhasset, Long Island, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1939 World's Fair demonstration house, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Daniel Superior house (Job# 819), Great Neck, Long Island, 1940-08 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Williams residence (Job #765), Rockville Center, Long Island, 1939-08 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Unknown residence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Drawings, 222 Jericho Turnpike. (Job #183) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Olive F. and Carl Johnson residence (Job #627), Garden City, Long Island, 1937-04 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - English town house (Job# 709), Garden City, L. I, 1938-08 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Unknown residence (Job# 538), Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Barbeque Pavilion, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Unknown residence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Studies, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Wrought iron stair rail (Job #289), 1930-08 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Watercolor renderings of unidentified country club house, Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Watercolors
  - Unidentified building (Job #835), 1940-10 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Garden plan, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Unidentified building, Undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Grace Church (Job# 640), Whitestone, Long Island, 1937-07 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Harold Jacobi residence (Job #548), Woodmere, Long Island., 1933 (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Unknown residence, Ft. Lauderdale, Florida, 1958 (Mapcase-folder 4)
  - Sanford Jacobi residence (Job# 559), Woodmere, Long Island, 1934 (Mapcase-folder 5)
  - Sadie Heyman residence (Job # 558), 1934 (Mapcase-folder 6)
  - Sign Company (Job# 584), 1935-09 (Mapcase-folder 7)
  - Zinn residence (Mapcase-folder 7)
  - Tucker house (Job #442), Garden City, Long Island, 1930-04 (Mapcase-folder 8)
  - Brown residence (Job #196), Undated (Mapcase-folder 9)
  - Community Church, Garden City, Long Island, 1936-06 (Mapcase-folder 10)
  - Blueprints of the Henry Pierson residence (Job# 398), Old Westbury, Long Island, 1929-07 (Mapcase-folder 11)
  - Unknown residence (Job# 512)), 1931-05 (Mapcase-folder 11)
  - Unknown residence (Job# 530)), 1932-03 (Mapcase-folder 12)
  - Harold Smith residence (Job# 387), Garden City, Long Island, 1929-06 (Mapcase-folder 13)
    Conceptual drawings
  - Harold (Harry) Smith residence (Job# 533), Garden City, Long Island, 1929-06 (Mapcase-folder 13)
  - Harold (Harry) Smith residence sketches, Garden City, Long Island, 1929-06 (Mapcase-folder 13)
  - Pennington residence (Job #603), Garden City, Long Island, 1936-07 (Mapcase-folder 14)
  - Duplex for Olive F. and Carl Johnson, Undated (Mapcase-folder 15)
  - Six unit apartment for Olive F. Tjaden (Job# 530), Undated (Mapcase-folder 15)
  - Unknown apartment buildings (Job# 28, 200, and 208), Undated (Mapcase-folder 16)
  - Unknown apartment buildings (Job# 425 and 819), Undated (Mapcase-folder 16)
  - Unknown residence (Job#389), 1929-05 (Mapcase-folder 17)
  - Hendricks Island Apartments, Fort Lauderdale, Florida., Undated (Mapcase-folder 18)
  - 97 Continental Avenue, Forest Hills, NY, Undated (Mapcase-folder 19)
  - Horace Hoffman residence (Job# 438), Garden City, Long Island, 1930-03-1930-08 (Mapcase-folder 20)
  - Feeley residence, Morristown, New Jersey, 1930 (Mapcase-folder 20)
  - Edith and Arthur Marks residence (Job# 585), Woodmere, Long Island, 1935-09 (Mapcase-folder 20)
  - Walter Lyon residence (Job# 473), Huntington, Long Island, 1930-10 (Mapcase-folder 20)
  - Pancake residence (Job# 415), Garden City, Long Island, 1929-10 (Mapcase-folder 21)
  - Pancake residence, Garden City, Ft. Lauderdale, Florida, 1930-07 (Mapcase-folder 21)
  - N. Dade Imported Motors, Miami, Florida, 1950-1951 (Mapcase-folder 21)
  - Ray C. Olson residence, Middle River, Ft. Lauderdale, Florida, 1956-12 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Includes correspondence
  - Ray C. Olson residence, Middle River, Ft. Lauderdale, Florida, 1956-12 (Mapcase-folder 21)
  - Unknown apartment building, Ft. Lauderdale, Florida, 1955-1960 (Mapcase-folder 22)
  - Unknown residence (Job# 582), 1935-07 (Mapcase-folder 23)
  - Inwood Beach Club, Long Island (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Exterior renderings
  - Inwood Beach Club (Job# 660), Atlantic Beach, New York, 1937-12 (Mapcase-folder 24)
  - Inwood Beach Club (Job# 660), Atlantic Beach, New York, 1937-12 (Mapcase-folder 35)
    Charcoal drawings
  - Unknown residence (Job# 519), 1931-08 (Mapcase-folder 25)
  - C. A. Hammann residence(Job# 406), Huntington, Long Island, 1929-08 (Mapcase-folder 26)
  - Shevlin residence (Job# 387), Garden City, Long Island, 1929-06 (Mapcase-folder 27)
  - Unknown residence (Job# 415), 1929-06 (Mapcase-folder 28)
  - Lannin residence on Salisbury Golf Link (Job# 340), Garden City, Long Island, 1928-11 (Mapcase-folder 29)
    Pen and ink drawings
  - Jehovah's Witnesses, Tamiami, Florida, 1954-10 (Mapcase-folder 30)
  - Raymond White residence (Job #420), Garden City, Long Island, 1954-10 (Mapcase-folder 30)
  - Herbert Rosengarten residence (Job #605), Woodmere, Long Island, 1936-07 (Mapcase-folder 30)
  - Frank Richards row houses (Job# 527), Forest Hills, Queens, 1932-02 (Mapcase-folder 31)
  - Baptist Church (Job# 710), Bellrose, Long Island, 1938-07 (Mapcase-folder 31)
  - W. H. Duryea residence (Job# 451), Garden City, Long Island, 1930-06 (Mapcase-folder 31)
  - Unknown Colonial style doctor's office and residence (Job# 622), Garden City, Long Island, 1937 (Mapcase-folder 32)
  - B. P. W. C. Club House, Ft. Lauderdale, Florida, Undated (Mapcase-folder 32)